#### Curriculum Vitae

#### Ryan Lovell

## rjl89@live.co.uk

https://github.com/RyanLovell89

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-lovell-b0733b170/

07867 418922

#### **Personal Details**

Full Driving Licence and car owner

## **Profile**

I look forward to any challenge, goals or objectives that are given to me and I am always striving for better ways of performing my job effectively.

I like to get on and complete a task that has been set, I can, however, adapt to changing needs. I enjoy being part of a team.

I am well organized and will undertake all tasks to the best of my ability. I will bring all my experience and enthusiasm with me to perform any job well.

## **Career History**

Berkshire Parts & Panels Ltd – 4<sup>th</sup> November 2019 – 25<sup>th</sup> November 2019 **Role: Business Development Manager (full time)** 

## **Main Jobs**

- Face to face customer sales
- Generating new business
- Maintaining current business
- Maintaining excellent relationships with customers
- Providing a full range of technical information on all products
- Sorting out customer discounts
- Generating quotes for customers
- Identifying new potential customers from provided databases
- Arranging meetings with buyers and business owners

PPG UK Ltd - August 2012 – 31st October 2019 (Redundancy) Role: Product Sales Executive (full time) August 2017 – 31st October

## **Quota & Achievements**

- FY18 Jan-Dec 2018 Quota £1.5m Actual £1.65m 110%
- FY17 Aug-Dec 2017 Ramp up Actual £1m

**Major Customers:** Bucher Municipal - £750K revenue Thompson UK - £250k Andover Trailers - £200k

Adams Morey Ltd / Greenhaus Group - £100k

## **Main Jobs**

- Face to face customer sales
- Maintaining customer stock controls
- Maintaining excellent relationships with customers
- Generating new business
- Creating offers to promote sales
- Maintaining customer loan stocks
- Sorting customer discounts on products
- Colour matching for customers on site
- Providing a full range of technical information on all products
- Ensuing customer payments are up to date

## Role: Counter Assistant (full time) August 2012 - August 2017

## **Main Jobs**

- Taking orders from customers via telephone, fax or email and booking them out
- Finding and printing off paint formulas
- Colour matching, mixing paint and primers
- Serving customer over the counter
- Ordering up goods from suppliers
- Checking off and putting deliverys away
- Booking in goods and batching up paperwork
- Helping customers out with technical paint support
- Ordering and organising paint tinters and equipment for paint scheme installations
- Help train new members of staff
- Aranging return to supplier forms when goods incorrectly supplied
- Sorting out stock levels either raising or lowering depending on customer demand
- Visiting customers to do stock control

Argos - November 2008 - August 2012

Role: Delivery Team Leader (part / full time)

**Role: Stock Assistant (part time)** 

## **Main Jobs**

- Serving customers on tills
- Serving customers on jewelry department
- Serving customers on customer services
- General tiding of the stockroom
- Pulling in the delivery off the lorry, double decker or normal size
- Putting delivery away
- Sorting out delivery errors
- Sorting out delivery paperwork
- Running a team of people

The Crown Pub - November 2011- March 2012 Role: Bar and Restaurant Staff (part time)

## Main Jobs

- Serving drinks and food
- Taking food and drinks orders
- General tiding of the pub
- Opening and closing the bar
- Restocking of drinks and snacks
- Sorting out the cellar

Rainbow Double Glazing - August 2007 - November 2008 Role: Builder / Window Fitter (full time)

#### **Main Jobs**

- Preparing windows to be fitted
- Fitting Windows
- Fitting glass
- Unloading and loading van of stock
- Cleaning, trimming and sealing windows
- General brick work

• Cleaning Up Work Site

Sainsburys - July 2006 – August 2007 Role: Food Counter Assistant (part time)

## Main Jobs

- Preparing food
- Cooking food
- Serving customers
- Cleaning ovens and counters
- Preparing meat and fish

## **Education:**

Code Institute 2020-2021 Courses Taken

• Full Stack Web Developer

## Queen Mary's College 2006-2007 Courses Taken

- Fitness Instructor Level 1
- GCSE English OCR Level 2 in Adult Literacy
- BTEC Sport

# Brighton Hill Community College 2001-2006 GCSE:

- Maths C
- English C
- Science C
- P.E B
- GNVQ ICT 4 Cs
- Prevocational Studies Bronze
- JSLA Pass

# **Additional Information**

I have a black Belt 2<sup>nd</sup> Dan in Ju-jitsu; I am also a qualified assistant teacher in the sport and have been for 8 years. I have studied Ju-jitsu since I was 5 years old. In my spare time I like to go to the gym or go to martial arts training. I also like to socialise, play football and other sports.

# References

Both personal and professional references can be provided upon request.